This fiction contains the following elements.
この物語はフィクションです。
Greeting y'all
皆様はじめまして、
I'll be the driver for this adventure. Call me Yue.
この旅の運転をしますユエです。
I'm Maki. Just freeloading Yue's motorcycle.
マキです。ユエのバイクに無断に乗ってます。
It's an unusual format with many flaws,  but wanted to log these memories.
ちょっと特殊な動画で至らない点が 多いと思いますが、記録を残したくて作っております。
Yeah, I might be an exchange student, but still unsure of my japanese.
そうね、留学生でも、まだ日本語に自信がない。
I guess that's what makes the video odd...
それが特殊にさせている理由かも。。。
No sweat, I can speak english for free after all.
大丈夫、こっちも英会話をタダでできるし〜
Free? I won't speak if you don't show me around
タダ～？連れて行ってくれないと口を利かないぞ～
Already going there myself so it's not a problem.
俺が行くついでだしそれぐらい
If you find the video too boring  or it doesn't suit your taste put a dislike,
詰まらないもしくは合わない場合は低評価を、
Otherwise stick around until the end.
そうでなければ最後まで楽しんでください。
Wonder how you manage to say this.
ほんとよく言えるね。。。
Find it odd to say.
恥ずかしくて言えん。。。
Wait? You don't have to say it?
えっ、言わなくていいの？
Nope
ノー
Cute
可愛ええ〜
Got my 2 wheel license!
二輪免許取ったぞ〜納車は10月上旬。これで風になれるぞ〜
Oh, congrats. Going somewhere?
おっ、おめでとう〜、どこか行くの？
Didn't plan anything yet.
そうだね〜、まだ決めていない。
Can you give me a lift to the airport when I'll go back to sis' place by the end of the month?
月末にお姉ちゃんの所に帰るけど、空港に送ってくれないかな？
Hmm, fine
ん～、OK
Want to focus for the first few rides so ain't putting any action cam yet, but afterwards.
最初は運転に集中したいから、 アクションカムはおいてないが次回から動画もちゃんと撮影しよ〜。
Actually you did wonder for a few on where to attach it and just gave up and left it home
本当はつける箇所を迷いに迷って、 結局アクションカムを家に忘れてきただけだよね
You didn't need to tell them...
イワナクテモイイデショウ。。。
So enjoy this part with pictures only.
ということで背景イラストで許してください
It's you first time editing so be carefull.  And no weird sentence or misspell.
動画編集も初めてだから無理しないように。 あと変な言い回しとか、誤字は気をつけてね。
Yah
は〜い
Take care. Be carefull until you get home.
気をつけてな、家に着くまでが移動よ
Thanks dad.
遠足か～
... Gotta get home too.  On way home I can make a small detour here and there.
。。。ぼちぼち帰るか。ついでにあそことあそこ行くか。
このバイクの所有者ですか？
Hey, are you the owner of this motorcycle?
Is she talking to me?
もしかして俺？
どれぐらいのパワーありますか？
How much power does you beast have?
Ermmm...
あ、えっ？
えーっと、パワー、CC？
Erm, power, cc?
CC? Ohhh, 400
CC？おー、フォーハンドレッド
400CCは結構小さいね。でも見た目はごついね。
Ow 400cc is pretty small. But looks beefy for a motorcycle of this range.
You've been riding for long?
どれぐらい乗ってる？
About 1 month?
1ヶ月間ぐらいですかね？
I've used one too. I must say I miss those days.
昔私も乗ってた。懐かしい。
I see
そうですか
Was fun talking to you. By the way your english is pretty good.
時間とってごめん。ちなみに英語上手～
Nono still beginer
いいえいいえまだまだです
Have a good one mate.
バイク楽しみな～
Take care
お気をつけて
Finally figured where to put this camera.
ふぅ、ようやくアクションカムの置き場所が決まった
Hope it'll look good on the handlebar
ハンドルマウントだし、大丈夫かな？
Riding a motorcycle is great
イヤーでもやっぱりバイク最高だわ
I used to ride a bicycle but had a hard time climbing hills when I went from Kumamoto to Nagasaki
元チャリダーだったが、 熊本から長崎行ったときは上り坂がきつかったな。。。
I can go anywhere with this
こいつとだとどこまでも行けそう
Made my heart of steel into a proper engine
心のエンジンを具現化したようだ
Uphill hairpin incoming! Tilt...
登りヘアピン、傾き～っと
Nailed it
ヨシ
Wasn't a mistake to choose the Honda 400x
車種はホンダ400Xにしてやはり間違いなかったわ
Since it's an adventure bike, it's ready for adventure
アドベンチャー最高、さすがAdventureバイク～
Yay wind!
風気持ちい～
Crimson trees
おっ？赤い～
Came at the right time
ちょうどいい時期にこれたな～
Pfiew, got on top. Didn't have any stall this time.
いや〜、登った。今回はエンスト無しで行けた〜。
Phew, finally got on top. Why was that part a trail…
はぁ、もうすぐ頂上か。途中土が多かったな。。。
Ah
ユエ： あっ マキ：あっ
You are the dude of the other day.
この前の人だよね
You are the person of the other day...  Wait did you come here walking?
あなたはこの前の外国人。。。って、えっ、ここまで徒歩で？
Yeah by foot.
そう、徒歩
Wow, you're very healthy!
すごい、体力あるんですね～
I'm healthy?
そんなに健康的か？
Forgot to ask last time, when did you start using the motorcycle?
前回聞き忘れたが、いつからバイクに？
Around the start of October
そうですね、10月上旬からですね。
Start of October? Wait, how far did you go in kilometers?
10月上旬？ちょっと待て、距離は？
About 2800 kilometers? (2021/11/28)
確か、2800キロぐらいかな？(2021/11/28時点)
What?
えっ？
Something wrong?
おかしい？
Nope, not at all. Enjoy your pictures.
いや、そうでもない。撮影楽しんで。
Thanks
ありがとう
Everyone has the same reaction...
なぜかみんな同じ反応なんだよな。。。
Just riding 200-300km per ride
走る距離は普段2、300キロで、
Up to 550km in 14 hours, 4 of which are used for resting...
10時間走って、4時間休んでも550キロぐらいなのに。。。
Time to go home
帰るか
Are your legs ok?
足大丈夫？
! You figured?
！気付いた？
I'll figure a way. Going slowly down.  Maybe find a taxi in the worst case.
どうにかするわ、ゆうっくり下山して、 それでもダメな場合はタクシーを呼ぶわ。
Want me to carry you?
送ろうか？
You, motorcycle, to city.
あなた、バイク、町へ。
M'kay, thanks for the lift mate.
ありがとう、お願いするわ。
Sorry but can carry the bag for me please?
ごめん、カバン代わりに持ってくれない？
OK, I can do that at least.
分かった、それぐらいなら。
! Was this...
！今。。。
Ready?
大丈夫？
No probs, let's go!
モンダイない、レッツゴー
Dooooone
終わったー
Perv... But yeah, now have to hope everyone will not hate it too much
変態。。。まーでも後は低評価の嵐が来ないのを願うだけ。。。
We did our best
ベスト出し切った。
Yeah, we did good
うん、頑張った
Going to upload!
アップするよ
「Hold me back!」 was it? (Untranslatable)
「押すな押すな」だったっけ？
Why do you know this expression?
ホントどこで覚えてくるの、すごいわ。
Just watching other's video
ほかの車載主の動画を見ただけ
isthatso...
ソウデスカ。。。
... From stupefaction I pressed the upload button... Que sera sera
あっ、驚いて押していた。。。ケセラセラ
Kesera Sera?
けせらせら？
I think it ment something along the lines of "Things bound to happen will happen"
なんか「なるようになる」、 「未来の出来事はどうせ起こる」っていう意味だったっけ？
Well, time to make our next one. Where are we going next?
次の動画を作らないと。どこ行く予定？
Please look forward to it
秘密です
Anywhere you want to go, but I have already a few ideas
ま～、マキさんのリクエストも大歓迎だが、
Since I need to edit and plan, I'll probably need roughthly 3 months
現時点で数か所行きたい所がある。
Booo, I'll help so make is faster.
えー、手伝うから～
I'm sure I'll find time between my classes.
勉強の間に時間ができると思う
Thanks
サンクス
I hate old litrature and geography
コテンチリキライ
I'll help... Wait I do not remember anything
こんど手伝う。。。あっ、やっ、俺も分からないか。。。
I'll help for english
えいごてつだう～
Gotta ask naration to Aoi later.
葵ちゃんに説明のナレーションをお願いしないと。